PRANITA GANDHI

LinkedIn Profile: www.linkedin.com/in/pranitagandhi

Portfolio Website: https://pranita-gandhi.netlify.com

07932476719 | pranita_gandhi@hotmail.com | Hounslow, London, United Kingdom

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Graduate Junior Full Stack Developer (JavaScript, Python) with an eye for detail, writing clean readable code and efficient debugging of code through portfolio projects.

Self-starter who has completed an array of assessed and personal projects to match UX/UI of the client.

Former Biochemistry/Research technician, co-author on 4 high-impact journal papers (including nature).

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- Graduate with a Diploma in Full Stack Software Development (Code Institute)
- Co-author on 4 high-impact journal papers' (highly skilled in problem solving) (Fruttiger Laboratory)
- Achieved two increment points for outstanding data administration work and stretching beyond objectives (UCL Department of Public Health and Epidemiology).

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- jQuery/JavaScript
- Bootstrap
- Materialize
- Git/GitHub
- Python

- Django
- Flask
- Heroku
- AWS S3
- Test Drive Development (Unit Testing- Python)

PORTFOLIO PROJECTS

- Front End Static Site on a band using only HTML, CSS and Bootstrap 3.8 The Who https://pranitastudent.github.io/Milestone-project/
- Interactive Front End Site creating an exam dashboard fictious student data represented in forms of
 pie charts, bar charts and line graphs (interactive) using HTML/CSS/Bootstrap and JavaScript in addition
 to front-end programming languages Exam Dashboard
 https://pranitastudent.github.io/Milestone-Second/
- Back End Site creating an online cookbook with search, filter, authentication and CRUD functions using front-end technologies in addition to Python, Flask and MongoDB – Gujarati FODMAP Cookbook http://guju-cookbook-fodmap.herokuapp.com/
- Back End Site creating a fictious ecommerce store using front-end technologies in addition to Python, Stripe, Django, PostgreSQL, Unit Testing, AWS S3 and Heroku – Pranita's T- Shirt Shop https://pranita-tshirt-shop.herokuapp.com/

EXPERIENCE

January 2019 - November 2019

Richmond Upon Thames College, Twickenham

Attendance Administrator

- Key player in answering calls, emails and text messages from students/parents/carers about attendance absences and referring sensitive student absences cases to welfare officer proactively.
- Executed highly accurate and precise data entry of 1000+ student entries into SQL databases (ProSolution packages) enabling efficient referral of students to welfare support as needed.
- Collaborated with the bursary team to process bursary forms and create and hand out meal vouchers to students when required.
- Proactively and efficiently completed over 100+ standard references for past/present students seeking employment.
- Efficiently handled the college GP clinic diaries, booked students appointments through face to face communication, liaised with GP's to cancel/book clinics when needed.

February 2018 – December 2018

Gap Year

Recovering from medical treatment

November 2017 - January 2018

Richmond Upon Thames College, Twickenham

Student Support Assistant

- Excellent customer service skills to diligently and politely answer and resolve queries regarding bursary payments from parents/students.
- Completed accurate data entry of 800+ student bursary in MS Excel and used MS Excel functions such as VLOOK to acquire data as needed.
- Coordinated the welfare officer diary to allow all students appointments to be booked in when needed.

September 2016 – September 2017

St Mary's University, Twickenham

Biochemistry Technician

- Instrumental in negotiating 10-15% discounts with scientific sales representatives and Capex procurement enabling organisational to stretch budget to procure more consumables and reagents for practicals.
- Managed, trained and taught final year student's ELISA and Molecular Biology techniques resulting in all students' completing and passing their dissertations.
- Generated and completed production of Health and Safety Risk assessments resulting in the team passing the Health and Safety assessment.

EDUCATION

Code Institute Bootcamp (accredited by Edinburgh Napier University)

Level 5 Diploma in Full Stack Software Development - 2020 Result: Second Class

Brunel University

MSc Molecular Medicine- 2008 Result: Merit